<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Sven's Blog</title>
  <subtitle>About Ruby on Rails and web development in general</subtitle>
  <id>https://svendittmer.github.io/blog</id>
  <link href="https://svendittmer.github.io/blog"/>
  <link href="https://svendittmer.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2016-09-24T08:44:00+02:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Sven Dittmer</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Setting up postgres on linux mint debian edition</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://svendittmer.github.io/blog/2016/09/24/setting-up-postgres/"/>
    <id>https://svendittmer.github.io/blog/2016/09/24/setting-up-postgres/</id>
    <published>2016-09-24T08:44:00+02:00</published>
    <updated>2016-09-24T10:28:23+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Sven Dittmer</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is a step-by-step guide to getting up and running with postgres on &lt;abbr title="Linux Mint Debian Edition"&gt;LMDE&lt;/abbr&gt;. I'm new to postgres, since I've only been working with mysql so far. I want to share with you the problems and solutions I encountered getting postgres up and running, hoping that it may help you setup postgres, too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Setting up postgres on my local machine wasn't as easy as I expected. I had to get it up and running when I started using heroku, where postgres is the default database. At some point, the tutorial required a working installation of postgres, without explaining how it's done. But even if you don't use heroku, postgres offers some advantages to you, especially when used in a rails app. In case you're interested, check the further reading section after you finished this article.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="installing-postgres"&gt;Installing postgres&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is actually simple, it takes two commands:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;~ $ sudo apt-get update
~ $ sudo apt-get install postgresql postgresql-server-dev-&amp;lt;required-postgres-version, e.g. 9.4&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;postgresql&lt;/em&gt; installs all you need to run the database, while &lt;em&gt;postgresql-server-dev-9.4&lt;/em&gt; is required to install the &lt;em&gt;pg&lt;/em&gt; gem later. You may also use Synaptics to install postgres if you prefer using a GUI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="getting-access"&gt;Getting access&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I tried the &lt;em&gt;psql&lt;/em&gt; command, I got this error:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Fatal: role lmde does not exist
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After some research, I learned that a role is what you would call a user in mysql. So psql tried to access the database using my username as role, and that role did not exist. When installing postgres a user account and a role called &lt;em&gt;postgres&lt;/em&gt; were created. So, in order to access the database, I had to login as &lt;em&gt;postgres&lt;/em&gt;, like so:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;~ $ su -
~ # su - postgres
~ $ createuser lmde --createdb
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;createuser&lt;/em&gt; is a utility command offered by postgres, which creates a role. Don't forget the &lt;em&gt;–createdb&lt;/em&gt; option, or &lt;em&gt;rake db:create&lt;/em&gt; will fail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is all I had to do to continue the heroku tutorial. If this guide doesn't work for you, here are some of the resources that helped me setup postgres:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.digitalocean.com/community/tutorials/how-to-setup-ruby-on-rails-with-postgres"&gt;How To Setup Ruby on Rails with Postgres | DigitalOcean&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.postgresql.org/docs/9.4/static/tutorial-createdb.html"&gt;PostgreSQL: Documentation: 9.4: Creating a Database&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Beginner Series</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://svendittmer.github.io/blog/2016/09/19/beginner-series/"/>
    <id>https://svendittmer.github.io/blog/2016/09/19/beginner-series/</id>
    <published>2016-09-19T22:04:00+02:00</published>
    <updated>2016-09-24T10:28:23+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Sven Dittmer</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today I'm starting a series of beginner tutorials for budding web developers. I expect the reader to have a basic understanding of the topic. My goal is to provide some best practices that go a little beyond "Hello World". The articles will cover Ruby on Rails, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap and some other related stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="articles-tagged-beginner-series"&gt;Articles tagged "beginner series"&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="/blog/2016/09/24/setting-up-postgres/"&gt;Setting up postgres on linux mint debian edition&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="/blog/2016/09/19/beginner-series/"&gt;Beginner Series&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>New Design</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://svendittmer.github.io/blog/2016/06/13/new-design/"/>
    <id>https://svendittmer.github.io/blog/2016/06/13/new-design/</id>
    <published>2016-06-13T22:31:00+02:00</published>
    <updated>2016-09-24T10:28:23+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Sven Dittmer</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Check out the new design of this website! I added a header to prevent all the
text from sticking at the top. Looks better now! 😸&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In case you're wondering why I didn't add a header before launching this site,
there's a good reason for that.
It took me weeks to choose the right blogging platform, and when I had
chosen Middleman, I thought I had to build some really fancy stuff, optimized
for SEO, using flexbox, customize Middleman and all that. I was busy doing that
for some time until I realized that I didn't have any imagination how my website
should look like (except from totally awesome!!!), and on top of that I had no
text or images to present.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I decided to start with a simple Bootstrap page,
no fancy stuff, and to add an article every day until the content would be worthy
of SEO, style and all that. Well, three articles is enough to justify adding
a header, I guess.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Deploying Middleman to Github Pages</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://svendittmer.github.io/blog/2016/06/12/deploying-to-github-pages/"/>
    <id>https://svendittmer.github.io/blog/2016/06/12/deploying-to-github-pages/</id>
    <published>2016-06-12T23:30:00+02:00</published>
    <updated>2016-09-24T10:28:23+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Sven Dittmer</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I've had quite some trouble deploying my site to github pages.
The reason is that the deploy needs to be configured differently,
depending on whether you create a website for a project or for your account.
The default configuration won't work if you're making a website for an
account. This configuration worked for me:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;activate :deploy do |deploy|
  deploy.deploy_method = :git
  deploy.branch = 'master'
end
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, note that the current version of middleman-deploy (1.0.0) doesn't seem to
do the trick, I had to use the alpha Version: &lt;code&gt;gem "middleman-deploy", "~&amp;gt; 2.0.0.pre.alpha"&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After figuring out how it works, I must say that I'm quite happy with the result:
The deploy works like a charm and I've got a free website now, ssl already included! 😄&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>First Blog Entry</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://svendittmer.github.io/blog/2016/06/12/first-blog-entry/"/>
    <id>https://svendittmer.github.io/blog/2016/06/12/first-blog-entry/</id>
    <published>2016-06-12T02:00:00+02:00</published>
    <updated>2016-09-24T10:28:23+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Sven Dittmer</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I've been playing with the thought of building my own blog for a few months, and now is the time I turn this thought into reality. Choosing a platform wasn't easy, and I considered using Wordpress, Ghost, Jekyll or Medium until I decided to dive into Middleman instead. I might still copy some articles to Medium though, since I am already registered at Medium and I spend at least a couple minutes every day to check out what's going on there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="why-middleman"&gt;Why Middleman?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, first of all I like the idea of creating static websites. Since I'm dealing with database-backed web-apps at work every day, it seemed to me that diving into this kind of technology might broaden my mind and enable me to look at building websites in a new, different way. Secondly, Middleman is based on Ruby, so I can bring in my experience as Ruby on Rails Developer and use my favorite Template Language Slim.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alright, this should be enough text for a first blog entry. Writing is done, now ship it!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
