<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Blog Name</title>
  <subtitle>Blog subtitle</subtitle>
  <id>http://blog.url.com/blog</id>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/blog"/>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2016-09-19T22:04:00+02:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Blog Author</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Beginner Series</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/blog/2016/09/19/beginner-series/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/blog/2016/09/19/beginner-series/</id>
    <published>2016-09-19T22:04:00+02:00</published>
    <updated>2016-09-19T22:17:45+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today I'm starting a series of beginner tutorials for budding web developers. I expect the reader to have a basic understanding of the topic. My goal is to provide some best practices that go a little beyond "Hello World". The articles will cover Ruby on Rails, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap and some other related stuff. The first article will be about saving records in ActiveRecord, possible gotchas and best practices.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>New Design</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/blog/2016/06/13/new-design/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/blog/2016/06/13/new-design/</id>
    <published>2016-06-13T22:31:00+02:00</published>
    <updated>2016-06-18T11:07:26+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Check out the new design of this website! I added a header to prevent all the
text from sticking at the top. Looks better now! 😸&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In case you're wondering why I didn't add a header before launching this site,
there's a good reason for that.
It took me weeks to choose the right blogging platform, and when I had
chosen Middleman, I thought I had to build some really fancy stuff, optimized
for SEO, using flexbox, customize Middleman and all that. I was busy doing that
for some time until I realized that I didn't have any imagination how my website
should look like (except from totally awesome!!!), and on top of that I had no
text or images to present.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I decided to start with a simple Bootstrap page,
no fancy stuff, and to add an article every day until the content would be worthy
of SEO, style and all that. Well, three articles is enough to justify adding
a header, I guess.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Deploying Middleman to Github Pages</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/blog/2016/06/12/deploying-to-github-pages/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/blog/2016/06/12/deploying-to-github-pages/</id>
    <published>2016-06-12T23:30:00+02:00</published>
    <updated>2016-06-18T11:15:33+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I've had quite some trouble deploying my site to github pages.
The reason is that the deploy needs to be configured differently,
depending on whether you create a website for a project or for your account.
The default configuration won't work if you're making a website for an
account. This configuration worked for me:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;activate :deploy do |deploy|
  deploy.deploy_method = :git
  deploy.branch = 'master'
end
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, note that the current version of middleman-deploy (1.0.0) doesn't seem to
do the trick, I had to use the alpha Version: &lt;code&gt;gem "middleman-deploy", "~&amp;gt; 2.0.0.pre.alpha"&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After figuring out how it works, I must say that I'm quite happy with the result:
The deploy works like a charm and I've got a free website now, ssl already included! 😄&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>First Blog Entry</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/blog/2016/06/12/first-blog-entry/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/blog/2016/06/12/first-blog-entry/</id>
    <published>2016-06-12T02:00:00+02:00</published>
    <updated>2016-06-13T00:03:30+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I've been playing with the thought of building my own blog for a few months, and now is the time I turn this thought into reality. Choosing a platform wasn't easy, and I considered using Wordpress, Ghost, Jekyll or Medium until I decided to dive into Middleman instead. I might still copy some articles to Medium though, since I am already registered at Medium and I spend at least a couple minutes every day to check out what's going on there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="why-middleman"&gt;Why Middleman?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, first of all I like the idea of creating static websites. Since I'm dealing with database-backed web-apps at work every day, it seemed to me that diving into this kind of technology might broaden my mind and enable me to look at building websites in a new, different way. Secondly, Middleman is based on Ruby, so I can bring in my experience as Ruby on Rails Developer and use my favorite Template Language Slim.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alright, this should be enough text for a first blog entry. Writing is done, now ship it!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
